Guide to the University Committee on Family and Child Care Issues records, 1986-1993
Duke University. University Archives
University Committee on Family and Child Care Issues records 1986-1993
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. University Committee on Family and Child Care Issues.
1.0 linear feet Extent: 1,000 Items
The University Committee on Family and Child Care Issues was created by President Brodie in 1990. The collection includes minutes, correspondence, reports and printed material ranging in date from 1986-1993.
RL.01554
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The University Committee on Family and Child Care Issues records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1994.
Historical Note
The University Committee on Family and Child Care Issues was created by President Brodie in 1990 and charged to address child and family care issues that remained within the University after the disbanding of the University Task Force on Child Care and the establishment of the Children's Campus.
Collection Overview
The collection includes minutes, correspondence, reports and printed material reflecting the work of the Committee and its following teams: Legislative Issues Team, Employee and Students Needs Assessment Team, Community Resources Team, and the Policy Team. Issues addressed by the Committee, as reflected in the records, include child care, quality of worklife, family sensitive policies and management practices, and family sensitive federal and state legislation. Other concerns reflected in the records are elder care as well as compensation and benefits. Included in the records are the working files of Lois Artis, former chairperson of the Committee. The material ranges in date from 1986-1993.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University. University Committee on Child Care and Family Issues; Work and family -- United States; Children -- Services for; Family -- Services for
Related Material
President H. Keith H. Brodie records, 1963-1994
University Archives. Duke University.
University Task Force on Child Care records, 1985-1990
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 2 Boxes
  - Lois Artis, Working Files, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1991-1992
  - Budget, Working File, 1990-1992
  - Committee Members, 1990-1993
  - Committee Reports, 1991-1993
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991
  - Legislation, 1990-1993
  - Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1991-1993
  - Printed Material (clippings, reports and articles), 1986-1991